

WEB DEVELOPER

Glasgow, Scotland

□ (+44) 752-312-7123 | 🗷 marv@marv-dev.com | 🌴 marv-dev.com | 🖸 DavidIrvine-TW | 🛅 davidirvinewebdev

"...The obstacle is the way."

Summary_

After 12 years overseas, I've recently returned to the UK to complete a career pivot from education to web development. I pride myself on being a lifelong learner, and a team player. I'm a determined individual committed to making meaningful contributions to innovative projects and initiatives. Willing to relocate and eager to get started.

Technical Skills

HTML · CSS · Javascript · React · Next.js · UI/UX · Version Control (Git) · SASS/SCSS · MUI · Tailwind · Node.js · APIs · NPM · CMS

Recent Employment History _____

Marv-Dev.com ✓ Scotland, UK

FREELANCE DEVELOPER January 2023 - present

· Working to expand my knowledge and technical skills by building custom sites/applications for patrons or just for fun.

Korean International School 🗹

Ho Chi Minh, Vietnam

February 2022 - February 2024

- SCHOOL TEACHER ICT/HISTORY
- Taught ICT, European history, and language skills to high school students.
- Developed original lessons from the national curriculum, ensuring alignment with educational standards and objectives.

Recent Developments _____

Vapester - Custom Shopify Storefront (password: eamaos) 🗹

TECH: HTML | CSS | JS | Liquid | AJAX | CMS

Dec 2023 - Jan 2024

- · Created an e-commerce web solution template from scratch, leveraging Shopify's CMS for efficient product management.
- Incorporated AJAX API for seamless cart data manipulation without page reloads, enhancing user experience.
- · Optimized page elements to decrease loading times and ensure cross-browser compatibility.

Kanban - Full-Stack Agile Task Management Web App 🗗

TECH: REACT | TAILWIND | FIREBASE | REDUX | FIGMA | NODE.JS

Oct - Nov 2023

- · Developed from a Figma design using React, Redux for state management, Firebase for auth and storage.
- Incorporated full CRUD features for usability enhancement.
- Designed reusable React components for tasks, subtasks, and columns to promote code reusability.

TrailerView - Full-Stack Entertainment Web App 🗹

TECH: NEXT.JS | TAILWIND | MONGODB | NEXTAUTH | API | NODE.JS | MUI

Aua - Oct 2023

- Built with Next.js for server-side rendering, routing, and API routes.
- Utilized TMDb API with Node.js for movie and TV show metadata retrieval.
- Employed SwiperJS for interactive section carousels, enhancing user engagement.

Education

Nottingham University

Nottingham, England, UK

Sept. 2018 - June. 2019

PGCEI - POST GRADUATE CERTIFICATE OF EDUCATION, INTERNATIONAL - A one-year postgraduate qualification in pedagogy.

BA(Hons) Multimedia Engineering

Glasgow Caledonian University

Glasgow, Scotland, UK

Sept. 2008 - June. 2012

- Studied multimedia technologies, digital media production, and web languages.

DAVID IRVINE · RÉSUMÉ MARCH 23, 2024